# **Bryan Pampola**

## SENIOR .NET DEVELOPER

bryanpampola@yahoo.com +63 995 8211068

https://bryanpampola.github.io/profile

## **SUMMARY**

Seasoned Software Engineer with 13 years' background in creating Web, Desktop, Mobile applications utilizing .NET and Cloud technologies. Highly experienced in all aspects of the software development lifecycle and end-to-end project management, from concept through to development and delivery.

#### **Specialties**

- Analyze system requirements and code based on best practices and standards
- Find solutions for technical problems, design project architecture, support team on solving difficult issues, make sure all teams follow the predefined architecture
- Write technical documents, checklist and guidelines
- Design and implement API services comply with security standards
- Meeting with customers to clarify requirements
- Perform overall code review & decide whether to refactor after each development phase
- Experience with migration applications from the legacy system to the new system with state-of-the-art technologies
- Define microservices/serverless architecture on cloud, design & implement for hosting large and/or complex applications

## Industry Experience

- Experience in various domains: ERP, Internal applications (HR, Payroll, Timekeeping, Service Desk) on Banking, Web Security, Manufacturing, IT industry
- Experience with building own products from scratch (startup) that need to solve business, technical & management issues, define developing strategy, scramble for market share

#### **EDUCATION**

Bachelor of Science in Information Technology (BSIT)
 STI College - Marikina, Marikina City, Philippines

## **TECHNICAL STACKS**

## Languages: .

NET (C#) and .NET Core (Backend)
Javascript, ReactJS and Typescript (Frontend)

#### **Applications:**

Window Forms and Console (Desktop)
Xamarin Forms (Mobile)
Web Forms, MVC, SOAP, REST API, ReactJS (Web)
Docker (Containerization)
Azure Functions (Cloud)

#### Databases:

SQL Server and Oracle (Relational)
SQLite, Postgres, Azure CosmosDB, AWS DynamoDB (NoSQL)
Entity Framework Core and Dapper (ORM)

#### Architectures:

Monolithic, Service Oriented (SOA), Microservices, Serverless

## Methodologies:

Scaled Agile, Scrum, Kanban, Waterfall

## **Technologies and Tools**:

Azure, Amazon Web Services (Cloud) Azure DevOps, Atlassian JIRA Bitbucket, Github (Repositories, CI/CD, Wiki, Boards) XUnit, Selenium, Postman, Application Insights and Splunk (Testing)

## **CERTIFICATIONS**

- SAFe Practitioner 6.0 (Scaled Agile Framework)
- Microsoft Certified: Azure Fundamentals (AZ-900)
- Microsoft Certified: Azure Al Engineer Associate (Al-102)

#### **WORKING EXPERIENCE**

## Pinion Software Consulting and Apps. (November 2019 - May 2023)

[Client] WE SELECT - Top recruitment agency in Sweden.

[Project] We Select Talent Software - revamp the old web application to improve overall architecture, structure and design.

#### [Role] Senior .NET Developer

- o Develop new features for the system related to automation like candidate hiring assessment and automatic product orders.
- o Apply and improve new and old third party integration
- o Write technical documents, prepare coding guidelines, and coding best practices.
- o Involves in project planning and discussion for betterment of the overall product.

## [Technologies]

- o C# .NET Core 6 (Backend)
- o Azure (SQL Server, Service Bus, Functions, App Insights, Storage)
- o React & TypeScript (Frontend)
- o Integrations Twilio Sendgrid (Email), Facebook (Marketing), Auth0 (Authentication), Slack (Webhooks)
- o Jira Board, Azure Devops CI/CD

## Yondu Inc. - Accenture Philippines (December 2017 - October 2019)

[Client] SOPHOS - One of the best CyberSecurity.

[Project] Service Oriented Architecture (SOA) Integrations Team - provides middleware services, integrations and support for all of the company's applications.

#### [Role] Senior .NET Developer

- o Led team of 3 junior software engineers undertaking the software life cycle, coding standards and overall applications.
- o Review pull requests and make it a good learning experience for the code owner.
- o Collaborate with other teams with regards to the application requirements.
- o Prioritized testing to ensure the quality and robustness of our services.

- o C# .Net Framework 4.5
- o AWS (S3, Cloudfront, EC2, DynamoDB, ElasticBeanstalk, CloudFormation, SQS)
- o Atlassian (Jira, Wiki, Stash, Confluence, CI/CD)
- o integrations Salesforce, IBM Cast Iron

## SHORE Solutions Inc. (July 2016 - September 2017)

[Client] ALTUS TRAFFIC - Australia's Largest Provider of Professional Traffic Control Services

[Project] Alloc8 ERP System - for handling Projects, Sales, Resource Management, Client Management and Reporting.

## [Role] FullStack Developer (.NET)

- o Programmatically design templates of the expenses reports for the clients purchases.
- o Learn and follow new coding standards implemented by the team lead.

#### [Technologies]

- o C# .Net Framework 4.6
- o Azure (DocumentDB, Service Bus)
- o Angular 4, Javascript
- o Material UI

[Project] My Altus Traffic Mobile App - simple scheduling and incident reporting mobile app for traffic controllers.

## [Role] Mobile Developer

- o Create a project from scratch and design the app UI.
- o Create the backend for the app to communicate to app service via Web API.
- o Develop a scheduler job for sending and truncating email messages and SMS.

#### [Technologies]

- o C# .NET 4.6 Framework, Xamarin Forms
- o Push Notification Service (APNS, GPNS)
- o Token lifecycle
- o Azure SQL Server, Window Service

## PRoV International (February 2016 - June 2016)

[Client] Underwriters Laboratories (UL) - is a global independent safety science company with more than a century of expertise innovating safety solutions.

[Project] Greenbox Hub - A windows mobile app for gathering factory data and overall checklist ensures quality and standards.

## [Role] Senior .NET Developer

- o Create 3 new template reports and undergo various tests to ensure correctness.
- o Collaborate with other teams with regards to the application requirements.

- o C# .Net Framework 4.5, Windows RT
- o SQLite, Dapper
- o SyncFusion tools

## Joe Riley & Associates (October 2015 - February 2016)

[Client] RCBC is one of the trusted commercial banks in the Philippines.

[Project] Access One - Retail Corporate Banking System.

## [Role] Senior .NET Developer

- o Develop Administrator module features.
- o Enhance batch applications (post dated bills and fund transfer) using Parallelism, Asynchronous programming and single logging.

## [Technologies]

- o C# .Net Framework 4.5
- o SQL Server 2014

## SLI Consulting Inc. (December 2014 - June 2015)

[Client] China Bank Savings (CBS) is the retail lending arm of China Banking Corporation (China Bank) and one of the largest savings banks in the country today.

[Project] Exception Handling System (EHS) - provides a complete checklist of document requirements and guidelines for old and new account holders.

[Project] Return to Sender Monitoring System (RTMS) - generates letters for newly opened accounts.

#### [Role] Web Developer

- o Led team of 1 junior software engineer undertaking the software life cycle, coding standards and overall applications.
- o Collaborate with other departments along with Business Analyst, regards to the application requirements and use-cases.

- o C# .NET and VB. NET Web Forms
- o Microsoft Office libraries
- o HTML, CSS, JQuery, Bootstrap

## NM Network Manager Sales Inc. (February 2014 - October 2014)

[Client] NMI - the #1 distributor of Kaseya (IT ERP Tool) in the Asia Pacific and #2 globally..

[Project] Online Service Desk System for Selayang Hospital, Malaysia

[Project] Online Service Desk System for Card MRI, Philippines

[Project] IT Asset Management System for Ayala Land Inc.

## [Role] Mid .NET Developer / Team Lead

- o Led team of 12 junior software engineers.
- o Review code and establish coding standards for junior developers.
- o Manual and remote deployments on clients servers.
- o Collaborate with other teams and projects.

#### [Technologies]

- o C# ASP .NET Web Forms, MVC
- o MS SQL Server 2012
- o IIS Server
- o Kaseya third-party integration
- o JQuery, Bootstrap

## Universal Storefront Services Corp. - Western Union (October 2012 - April 2013)

[Client] USSC is the number one agent of Western Union in the Philippines...

[Project] Employee Information System (EIS) - HR and Payroll system, attendance, work schedule and reports.

[Project] Employee Information System (EIS) - HR and Payroll system, attendance, work schedule and reports.

## [Role] Web Programmer

- o Enhance old and new features by refactoring old codes and implementations.
- o Created the RAMS project from scratch, from planning to development to deployment.

- o C# ASP .NET Web Forms
- o MSSQL Server 2010
- o IIS Server

## Primover Consultancy Services, Inc. (December 2017 - October 2019)

[Client] Avon - The world's leading direct seller of cosmetics and skincare.

[Project] IOU System - Incentive programs for Avon managers and area heads.

## [Role] .NET Developer

- o Create new small desktop apps for system support and incentive programs.
- o Experienced data mining on different servers and databases.
- o Generate queries and scripts and various company reports.

## [Technologies]

- o C# .Net Framework 4.0 Window Forms
- o Oracle Toad, PL/SQL

# LBP Resources and Development Corporation (June 2011 - December 2011)

[Client] Philippine Deposit Insurance Corp (PDIC) - is a government instrumentality created in 1963 by Republic Act 3591, as amended, to insure the deposits of all banks.

[Project] One Claim System - Claiming system used for closed bank departments and depositors.

## [Role] **Programmer**

- o Office and field work, assigned to 5 locations in the Philippines.
- o Experienced extracting different banking system databases.
- o Support both technical and software issues on the field.
- o Create system support and enhancement on OCS.

- o Visual Basic 6, VB .NET 2010
- o SQL Server 2010
- o MS Access, FoxPro, COBOL, C++.